Quijano Chavez Carlos Victor

Master Student en Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul

🛮 +55 (51) 984733342 🛛 carlos.chavez@inf.ufrgs.br 🔘 cquijanochavez@gmail.com

i Born on January 23, 1994 (26 years old) in Moquegua, Peru



Computer Science lover with experience in HCI research, Virtual Reality, and development skills. I am currently a Master's student in Computer Science at the Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS) in Porto Alegre, Brazil. My current research interest is Immersive Analytics. My dissertation focuses on applying engaging, embodied display and interaction techniques for data visualization and visual analytics in immersive environments. I want to continue acquiring research skills and evolve projects that help science and my personal growth.



FORMATION

- 2018 Master Stundent in Federal University Rio Grande do Sul - Brazil (Research area - Immersive Analytics)
- Graduated in National University of San Agustin (Computer Science)



PUBLICATIONS

AN IMMERSIVE APPROACH BASED ON TWO LEVELS OF INTERACTION FOR EXPLORING MULTIPLE COORDINATED 3D VIEWS

2021

Paper 🗘 github.com/cquijanoch/IMMultipleView 🖸 Demo Video

Carlos Quijano-Chavez, Luciana Nedel and Carla M. D. S. Freitas

Human-Computer Interaction – INTERACT 2021. Springer International Publishing.

Multiple Coordinated Views | Virtual Reality | Immersive Analytics

COMPARING SCATTERPLOT VARIANTS FOR TEMPORAL TRENDS VISUALIZATION IN IMMERSIVE VIRTUAL ENVIRONMENTS

2021

Under review 🗘 github.com/cquijanoch/VRTrendVis 🖸 Demo Video

Carlos Quijano-Chavez, Luciana Nedel and Carla M. D. S. Freitas IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics.

Evaluation Trends Visualization 3D Scatterplots Virtual Reality Immersive Analytics



PROJETS

DIA.BR 2018 - 2020

Member

The project aims to study and develop alternatives for interface modules with the core of the DIA.BR simulation system. The simulation system aims to support the geochemical modeling of diagenetic processes. The generation of data from these simulations will provide a better understanding of the development of diagenetic reactions in time and space, as well as their influence on the quality and heterogeneity of hydrocarbon reservoirs.

C++ Qt CMake SQLite

Annelida 2020

The objective of this project is to develop a control and sensing system for inspection and actuation vehicles in production lines, for unclogging and maintenance of 4" to 10" pipelines that have been obstructed by hydrates or paraffins, in a semi-autonomous way. The operation of the locomotion and clearance system will be carried out through a highly usable interface to be developed. The interface (VR version included) will also handle fault signaling and recovery and will provide a means of exploiting the data collected during operation.

C# Unity SteamVR



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

September 2020 Currently

Software Developer, NEOGRID, Porto Alegre-Brazil

- > Responsible for the development of applications that make up the data platforms used in the solutions and products of Neogrid.
- > Back-end developer focused on providing solutions to requests with great concurrence.
- > Reviewer and contributor of ideas for solutions architecture.

NET C# Azure Java SQL Server

November 2017 March 2018

Software Web Developer, WMPERU, Arequipa-Peru

- > Development of Front-end architecture.
- > Development of Claims module.

VsCode Angular Symfony MySql

May 2017 October 2017

Java Software Developer, UNSA, Arequipa-Peru

- > Development of BPM for Budget module.
- > Integration with SIAF with JMS.
- > Knowledge of Public Systems oriented to the government areas.

JBoss Eclipse Maven Angular EJB JPA PostgreSql FoxPro

September 2016 April 2017

Java Software Developer, GLOBAL SYSTEM AND CONSULTING, Arequipa-Peru

- > Development of Parent, Student and Staff Assistance modules.
- > Development of analytical reports.

GlassFish Netbeans Maven AngularJs EJB JPA PostgreSql

June 2016 August 2016

Java Software Developer, META Innova, Arequipa-Peru

- > Maintenance of tax management system.
- > Migration of region municipality data.
- > Development of analytical reports.

JBoss Eclipse Maven JSF Hibernate SQL Server



Programming Java (JEE, JSE), .NET,C#,Javascript, C++, PHP, Typescript, R

Frameworks Spring, Spring Boot, Ionic 3, Entity Framework, Angular, JSF, JBoss RichFaces, Bootstrap

Databases DB2, Oracle Database, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite

Development Tools Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, Eclipse, Unity, Visual Studio Code, Maven, Ant, SVN, git

Operating systems Windows Server, Windows Desktop, Linux Redhat, Linux Centos

ner Azure, Architecture SOA, Technologies BPM, 3D Game platforms, Methodology RUP SCRUM





♣ INTEREST AREAS

- > Data Visualization
- > Virtual/Augmented Reality
- > Human-computer interaction